hey everybody welcome to this B1 English
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as I speak before we
start remember to download the listening
Time Podcast and if you want my
specialized training to help you improve
your listening skills then become a
member at patreon.com listening time and
if you become a listening Time family
member then you'll receive my Advanced
podcast episodes which will help you
reach an advanced level of listening
okay today I'm going to talk about
college dorms this is a topic that a lot
of people outside the U.S find
interesting because most people in other
countries don't live in dorms when
they're in college so first of all what
are dorms these are residential
buildings located on University campuses
where students can live another way that
you can think about them is like
apartment buildings for college students
people almost always live with roommates
in these dorms either sharing the common
area or sharing a bedroom even the size
of dorm rooms varies and you'll probably
pay more from more space so which
students usually live in these dorms
well first and second year students
often prefer living in dorms rather than
in apartments off campus one of the main
reasons why these students choose to
live in the dorms is because it
immediately connects them with other
students and allows them to make friends
there's definitely a sense of community
in each dorm building so a lot of people
feel like they'd be missing out on this
if they lived off campus however not as
many older students choose to live in
the dorms there are still definitely a
lot of third and fourth year students
living on campus but a lot of them get
tired of dorm life after a couple years
needless to say there are some
disadvantages of this dorm life the main
one is that you don't really have much
privacy a ton of first-year students
have to share a bedroom with another
person and sometimes it's two or three
other people and so you can also imagine
what it would be like if you didn't like
these roommates you can get into all
kinds of arguments because you're
sharing such a small space with them one
other thing that could be considered a
negative about living in the dorms is
that a lot of these students only eat
from the University dining hall at
universities the dining hall is the
place where you eat your meals and it's
buffet style all you can eat sure dining
hall food can be good but you can
definitely get tired of eating this food
every day and a lot of first-year
students gain a lot of weight because of
how much they eat at this dining hall so
lastly let me just talk about my
experience in the dorms I lived in a
dorm for my third and fourth year of
college the good thing was that I lived
in a special dorm that was mostly for
third and fourth year students and in
this dorm I had my own bedroom which was
great however I didn't really like
sharing the kitchen and living room with
other people it was a little
uncomfortable and also I had some
roommates that weren't very responsible
and didn't clean up after themselves so
overall it wasn't that great of an
experience for me alright that's all for
today remember to download my free
listening Time Podcast and become a
member at patreon.com listening time if
you want my specialized training which
will help you understand native speakers
and if you want to reach an advanced
level of listening then become a
listening Time family member and you'll
receive my Advanced podcast also
subscribe to the channel click on the
bell and follow us on Instagram I'll see
you next time